<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Posts on Film - GKH Photo</title>
    <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent Posts on Film - GKH Photo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Geoff Holden 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:34:11 -0230</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://film.gkhphoto.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Tanks &amp; Reels</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/tanks_reels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 16:39:21 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/tanks_reels/</guid>
      <description>These are the tanks I have for developing film. They were all given to me when I started my first darkroom. I usually use the plastic tank and reels, because it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to load the film onto the reel (and the reel is adjustable for different film sizes). The downsides to the plastic ones are that you can&amp;rsquo;t load the film at all unless the reel is perfectly dry (I know this from experience, as I had to fumble around in the dark to find the stainless reel one time), and that they use a little more developer to cover the reel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/mixing_chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:02:27 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/mixing_chemistry/</guid>
      <description>I got my film developing chemistry mixed up last night (Kodak D-76, and Kodak Fixer). I have four exposed rolls in the fridge, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to start processing them.
   Mixed Chemistry   I keep my D-76 in small (591mL/20oz) pop bottles; this way I only ever have one partially full bottle, and as long as it&amp;rsquo;s at least half full, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to squeeze the air out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Rangefinder Focus Modification</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:28:54 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</guid>
      <description>I came across this simple hack the other day and quickly applied it to my Canonet. If the second image of the rangefinder is getting dim, it can be difficult to focus, especially in darker environments. If you can darken the main viewfinder, then the second image can compete and be visible. The trick is to darken just the centre of the main viewfinder with a piece of black tape (or even a black marker) so that the second image is easily visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonet as Teacher</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:22:53 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</guid>
      <description>Mostly inspired by Mike Johnston&amp;rsquo;s The Leica as Teacher post. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to primarily use my Canonet 28 for a while. Despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s probably not the best camera for the type of photography that I like taking (more landscape, less street), removing the distraction of multiple lenses, colour filters, etc. for a while should make me a better photographer in general.
I am not committing to a particular shooting or printing schedule, or to a set length to the project, just because I think with other life commitments, I&amp;rsquo;d be setting myself up to fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canon AE-1</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/ae-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/ae-1/</guid>
      <description>Canon AE-1   This, along with the AV-1, was one of the first film cameras that I purchased in 2009 that started me down this rabbit hole. I got both cameras, the power winder, and a 50mm ƒ/1.8 all for either $25 or $30 from a local seller. One of the cameras had some light leaks when I ran my first test roll through it, so I stripped out the old seals and replaced them with some adhesive-backed black felt from a craft store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canon AV-1</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/av-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/av-1/</guid>
      <description>Canon AV-1   This, along with the AE-1, was one of the first film cameras that I purchased in 2009 that started me down this rabbit hole. I got both cameras, the power winder, and a 50mm ƒ/1.8 all for either $25 or $30 from a local seller. One of the cameras had some light leaks when I ran my first test roll through it, so I stripped out the old seals and replaced them with some adhesive-backed black felt from a craft store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canon Canonet 28</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/canonet_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/canonet_28/</guid>
      <description>Canonet 28   I picked up this camera on eBay in 2009 for less than $20. The only issue with it is that it requires a PX625 mercury battery that is no longer readily available. Without the battery installed, it can only operate at a fixed shutter speed of 1&amp;frasl;30 with a manually set aperture. On many of these older cameras, the mercury cell was used because it has a stable voltage&amp;ndash;it stays at 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympus Trip 35</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/trip35/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/trip35/</guid>
      <description>This is another camera that I picked up from a local seller. To be honest, I bought this one mostly because of the cult classic status that it seems to have, so I figured I had to try it. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple camera, it&amp;rsquo;s fully automatic, powered by a selenium cell surrounding the lens, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need batteries at all. It&amp;rsquo;s set up for zone focus, so there&amp;rsquo;s no double image rangefinder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pentax K1000</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/k1000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/k1000/</guid>
      <description>Pentax K1000   Vivitar 35-70mm ƒ/2.8-3.8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yashica A</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/yashica-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/yashica-a/</guid>
      <description>Yashica A   This camera and the Yashica Mat-124G are from my father (I believe the 124G is officially a loan). I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually shot with either one yet, but I do have a few rolls of T-Max 100 in 120 cold storage and ready to go; part of the issue there is that my enlarger can&amp;rsquo;t project medium format without an expensive upgrade kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yashica Mat-124G</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/yashica_mat-124g/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:15:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/cameras/yashica_mat-124g/</guid>
      <description>Yashica Mat-124G   This camera and the Yashica A are from my father (I believe this one is officially a loan). I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually shot with either one yet, but I do have a few rolls of T-Max 100 in 120 cold storage and ready to go; part of the issue there is that my enlarger can&amp;rsquo;t project medium format without an expensive upgrade kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beseler Printmaker 35</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/printmaker35/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 09:37:45 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/printmaker35/</guid>
      <description>Printmaker 35   This is a small enlarger that I received with my initial batch of darkroom equipment. I picked up the manual on eBay afterwards, partially to know for sure where the condenser lens goes (on the bottom of the lamp housing, not on one of the &amp;lsquo;shelves&amp;rsquo;). It&amp;rsquo;s a condenser enlarger, with a 50mm lens installed for 35mm prints. It can project up to 11x14&amp;rdquo; on the baseboard, and larger if you reverse the column and project onto the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/darkroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:53:56 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/darkroom/</guid>
      <description>Finished Darkroom   My darkroom is a 9&amp;rsquo;4&amp;rdquo; × 6&amp;rsquo;4&amp;rdquo; room in my basement. Along one side is a custom cabinet with both open and closed storage, and a single drawer underneath. The top is some kitchen counter top that I salvaged when the installers put a scratch in it. Above the cabinet, I strung some rope between two L-brackets that I can use to hang prints to dry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>