<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Film - GKH Photo</title>
    <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Film - GKH Photo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Geoff Holden 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:34:11 -0230</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Film Processing Session</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/second_film_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:37:00 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/second_film_processing/</guid>
      <description>I processed and scanned another two rolls of film a few days ago. One roll was freshly shot a couple of weeks ago in the Stephenville area. The other one was left in the camera with some shots exposed in 2012, 2015, and the last ten only a few weeks ago. This was all hand-rolled Kodak Tri-X, developed in D-76. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to shoot and process another few rolls before I get into the darkroom and start printing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Film Developed in the New Darkroom</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/first_film/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:09:09 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/first_film/</guid>
      <description>I developed my first rolls of film in the new darkroom. One roll was from last week, the other was one that was shot ages ago and forgotten in the fridge.
   Film Developing Tools   I used my plastic tank and reels and D-76 in the 1:1 dilution. I get all my development times from the massive development chart and their Android app (which doubles as my timer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/mixing_chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:02:27 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/mixing_chemistry/</guid>
      <description>I got my film developing chemistry mixed up last night (Kodak D-76, and Kodak Fixer). I have four exposed rolls in the fridge, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to start processing them.
   Mixed Chemistry   I keep my D-76 in small (591mL/20oz) pop bottles; this way I only ever have one partially full bottle, and as long as it&amp;rsquo;s at least half full, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to squeeze the air out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Rangefinder Focus Modification</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:28:54 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</guid>
      <description>I came across this simple hack the other day and quickly applied it to my Canonet. If the second image of the rangefinder is getting dim, it can be difficult to focus, especially in darker environments. If you can darken the main viewfinder, then the second image can compete and be visible. The trick is to darken just the centre of the main viewfinder with a piece of black tape (or even a black marker) so that the second image is easily visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonet as Teacher</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:22:53 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</guid>
      <description>Mostly inspired by Mike Johnston&amp;rsquo;s The Leica as Teacher post. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to primarily use my Canonet 28 for a while. Despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s probably not the best camera for the type of photography that I like taking (more landscape, less street), removing the distraction of multiple lenses, colour filters, etc. for a while should make me a better photographer in general.
I am not committing to a particular shooting or printing schedule, or to a set length to the project, just because I think with other life commitments, I&amp;rsquo;d be setting myself up to fail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>