<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Film - GKH Photo</title>
    <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Film - GKH Photo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Geoff Holden 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:34:11 -0230</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Rangefinder Focus Modification</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:28:54 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/rangefinder_mod/</guid>
      <description>I came across this simple hack the other day and quickly applied it to my Canonet. If the second image of the rangefinder is getting dim, it can be difficult to focus, especially in darker environments. If you can darken the main viewfinder, then the second image can compete and be visible. The trick is to darken just the centre of the main viewfinder with a piece of black tape (or even a black marker) so that the second image is easily visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonet as Teacher</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:22:53 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/blog/canonet_as_teacher/</guid>
      <description>Mostly inspired by Mike Johnston&amp;rsquo;s The Leica as Teacher post. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to primarily use my Canonet 28 for a while. Despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s probably not the best camera for the type of photography that I like taking (more landscape, less street), removing the distraction of multiple lenses, colour filters, etc. for a while should make me a better photographer in general.
I am not committing to a particular shooting or printing schedule, or to a set length to the project, just because I think with other life commitments, I&amp;rsquo;d be setting myself up to fail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>