<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Equipment on Film - GKH Photo</title>
    <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Equipment on Film - GKH Photo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Geoff Holden 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 19:34:11 -0230</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega C700</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/omega_c700/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 14:23:44 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/omega_c700/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my new enlarger. Saved from the garbage, and I think it was partially assembled and never used. From my brief research on the matter, these were sold without a lens or negative carrier included, and I think the original purchaser didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this, so the enlarger was never used. I managed to secure myself a 35mm negative carrier and both 50mm and 75mm enlarging lenses. I drew up the outline for the 35mm carrier, as well as a 6×4.5cm, and a 6×6cm and had them laser cut out of acrylic. The bottom piece is &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo; black acrylic, the top is &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;rdquo; clear that&amp;rsquo;s been spray painted (top and sides only) flat black to stop any stray light. I&amp;rsquo;m including the file I used here: 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/omega_c700/Negative%20Carriers.pdf&#34;&gt;

Negative Carriers

&lt;/a&gt;


.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Tanks &amp; Reels</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/tanks_reels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 16:39:21 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/tanks_reels/</guid>
      <description>These are the tanks I have for developing film. They were all given to me when I started my first darkroom. I usually use the plastic tank and reels, because it&amp;rsquo;s so easy to load the film onto the reel (and the reel is adjustable for different film sizes). The downsides to the plastic ones are that you can&amp;rsquo;t load the film at all unless the reel is perfectly dry (I know this from experience, as I had to fumble around in the dark to find the stainless reel one time), and that they use a little more developer to cover the reel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beseler Printmaker 35</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/printmaker35/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 09:37:45 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/printmaker35/</guid>
      <description>Printmaker 35   This is a small enlarger that I received with my initial batch of darkroom equipment. I picked up the manual on eBay afterwards, partially to know for sure where the condenser lens goes (on the bottom of the lamp housing, not on one of the &amp;lsquo;shelves&amp;rsquo;). It&amp;rsquo;s a condenser enlarger, with a 50mm lens installed for 35mm prints. It can project up to 11x14&amp;rdquo; on the baseboard, and larger if you reverse the column and project onto the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom</title>
      <link>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/darkroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:53:56 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://film.gkhphoto.com/equipment/darkroom/</guid>
      <description>Finished Darkroom   My darkroom is a 9&amp;rsquo;4&amp;rdquo; × 6&amp;rsquo;4&amp;rdquo; room in my basement. Along one side is a custom cabinet with both open and closed storage, and a single drawer underneath. The top is some kitchen counter top that I salvaged when the installers put a scratch in it. Above the cabinet, I strung some rope between two L-brackets that I can use to hang prints to dry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>